Guide to the Zan Gibbs Riot Grrrl Zine Collection 1987-2003 (bulk 1992-1997) MSS 364
Fales Library and Special Collections
Zan Gibbs Riot Grrrl Zine Collection
Bulk, 1992-1997
1987-2003
MSS 364
Fales Library and Special Collections
3.75 linear feet (9 boxes)
The Zan Gibbs Riot Grrrl Zine collection consists of zines collected by Gibbs while she was involved in the Riot Grrrl movement in the early to mid-1990s, in Washington, DC, Vancouver, BC, and Portland, Oregon. While living in Vancouver, Gibbs started the Canadian version of Riot Grrrl Press, distributing zines through the mail throughout Canada.
Provenance
The collection was donated to the Fales Library in 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Arrangement
The Collection is arranged into one series, alphabetically by zine title.
Biographical note
Zan Gibbs grew up in Montreal, Quebec before moving to Washington, DC when she was 13. She was introduced to the Riot Grrrl movement in the early 1990s in DC via the punk rock music scene. She attended her first Riot Grrrl meeting at the Positive Force house when she was 16, and remained active in the movement for over 5 years. At 18 she moved to Vancouver BC, and with her already extensive zine collection she began the Canadian version of Riot Grrrl Press, distributing zines through the mail throughout Canada, while Riot Grrrl Press USA handled the distribution everywhere else.
When Gibbs was 22 she moved to Portland Oregon, and focused on starting a queer youth drop-in center for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer and questioning youth 24 and under. She helped found and then worked at that at-risk youth center for 12 years, and earned a bachelors degree in social work. She currently works with low-income adults in subsidized housing, and is considering getting a master's degree in public health.
Scope and Content
The Zan Gibbs Riot Grrrl Zine Collection consists of fanzines collected by Zan Gibbs during the early and mid-1990s, while living in Washington DC, Vancouver BC, and Portland, Oregon.
Fanzines.; Feminism.; Feminist music.; Political activists.; Punk rock music.; Queer theory.; Riot grrrl movement.; Teenage girls.
- Series I: Zines, TBD
  - The Adventures of Big Girl, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - After Sugar Glow #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alien #6, 8, 10, 11, 13, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alien Girl, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Altocumulus Undulatus #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Amazon Anxiety #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - And Sometimes We Reach For Nothing, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Another Book Part One, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Another Day in Paradise, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - April Fools Day, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aqua: Anarcho Queers Undermining Authority, undated, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Beri-Beri #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bite Me Bitch #1, 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - A Bitter Chain Link Fence, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blonde: Act 1, 2, 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Blonde: Join the Party, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bloody Knuckles Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Blue Roses #3, 4, 5, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Book of Rules, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brillantine, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Broke Up, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bruisers #1, 2, 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Busy Bea's Bush #3, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Butterfly #3, 4, undated, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Candles for Girls, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Carmel #4, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Channel Seven, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Chestlick #1, undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Coal for Eyes, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Confessional Poetry #2, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Conscious Clit, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Construction Paper #1, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Crankpot #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cross My Heart (Hope to Die), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cry Cry Cry..., undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cyanide #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Daddy's Little Girl, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Death Song, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Design #816 #6, 7, 8, 12, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Destroy Yr Valentine, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Deviance #1, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Diagnosis #1, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Discharge #2, 3, 5, 6, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Doris #5, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Drop Dead, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Effective Repetition, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Embracing Without Touching, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Epson Energy #2, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Evolution of a Race Riot, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Extra Butter on My Popcorn, Please, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Fantastic Fanzine #1, 2, 3, 3.5, 4, 4.5, 6, undated, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Fern #6, 7, 8, 10, 11, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Firecracker #1, 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fix Me, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Fragments, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Freaked Out, undated, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Free Lost Girl #3, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - From the Pen of a Liberated Woman #1, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Functioning In This Voice #1, 2.25, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Funeral #2, 3, undated, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gag Mee!, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Gift Idea #1, 1.5, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Girl Fiend #7, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - [Girl Name], 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Girl Germs #2,4, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gobstopper #2, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Goddess Juice #3, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Golden Heart, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Growing Pains #1, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - H.A.G. #4, 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Hands Off #1, 5, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - A Handy-Dandy Teeny-Weeny Guide to Zines, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Hanging Out, [1995] (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - I Hate This Part of Texas #4, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Healing Stone #1, 2, 3, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Hell's Acre #.5, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Hessian Obsession #1, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Hey Ackley Kid, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Hey Mexican!, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Hiding Place #2, undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Hit It or Quit It, undated, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Hive Queen #2, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Honey Suck, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Hope, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Hothead Paisan #19, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - How Long Do You Have?, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Humor and Dark Truth, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - I (Heart) Me, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - I Hit Back #1/Kitty #2, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - I Love You More, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - I Woke Up in Flames One Day, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - I'm Asking You Mister and You're Looking at Me, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - I'm Not a Poet and I Know It: Not Poetry By Some Dumb Girl, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - I'm So Fucking Beautiful #2.5, 3, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Impossible Schizoid Girl, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Insterbate and Destroy, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Insult to Injury, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - It's a Nice Night for a Walk, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - I've Got Angels in My Head, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Jaded #2, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Josh, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Jungle Gym, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Juryrig, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Just Add Water #2, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Kitten #9, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Kitty Girl, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Kult Princess Suicide #5, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Kusp #1, 3, 1995, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Last Half and Thus Far, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Let's Play Grrrl #3, [1993] (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Letters to Celebrities, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Lies and Scandals!, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Listen Up, OK? The Trish Kelley Experience, undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Literal Bitch, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - The Lost Generation #1, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Love Letters #1, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Luna, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Mad Love #1, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - The Make-Out Club #7, 8, 9, 10, 12, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Malefice #1, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Marika: Bi, May and Erika #1, 2, 3, [1993], undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - "Maybe" She Said #3, 4, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Meat Hook #1, 2, 3, 1990, 1992, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Memo Pad Mafia, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Men Against Sexism, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mestiza, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Midwest Girl Fest, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Missed the Boat, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Misunderstanding Silent Mirrors, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - More Stuff By Some Dumb Girl, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Ms. America Zine #3, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - My Cute Little Fists, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - My Favorite Picture, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - My House, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - My Life With Evan Dando, Popstar, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Nerd Girl #4, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Nerdy Grrrl Revolution #2, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - No Comment, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Now, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Now I Swallow Your Pants #2, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - OBEAH, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - The Other Half of What I Should Tell You, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Our Dirty Little Secret, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Out of the Vortex, 1994, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - P is for Pretty #5, 6, 7, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Painter Lewis #4, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Paintspot #4, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Paliopolis Loves Me, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Pander, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - ...Pants on Fire, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pardon Me Boy, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Pasty #1, 2, 1994, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Patricia, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Photobooth Toolbox #1, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Posses, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Power Candy #14, 16, 17, 1995, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pussy Cat Vision #2, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Queen Bee Creations, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Quiet Nights of Quiet Stars, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Grrrl Revolution - Riot Grrrl DC, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Grunge Gerl, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Radical Women in the House of Labor: A Historic Re-entry, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - [Rage Whistle], undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - The Rainy Day Chronicles, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Random Thoughts #3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Rampage #2, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Rape, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Raw, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Reclaiming My Name #2, 5, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Reclaiming My Name #7 / Hands Off #4, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Reinventing the Real, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Reggae Chicken, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Render, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Ring of Fire #2, 3, [1996], undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Riot Grrrl Arcata/Eureka #10, 11, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Riot Grrrl [DC] #3, 11, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Riot Grrrl! [New England] #1, 3, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Riot Grrrl Press, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Riot Grrrl! A Valley Grrrl Production, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Riot Grrrl Vancouver #2, 5, 6, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Abstract
    Riot Grrrl [Vancouver] no. 5
    Writings in this zine critique mainstream ideals of beauty, express nostalgia for youth and girlhood, question established and traditional careers and lifestyles, and talk about revolution. Other themes include equality in sexual relationships and frustration with them, straight edge and vegan advocacy, and danger signals to watch for in men. A word search, natural and homeopathic health remedies, excerpts from famous female writers concerning men, a David Wojnarowicz piece, and zine lists and reviews are included. Discussions on riot grrrl include different forms of the movement, reactions to stereotypes, and chapter information.
  - Riot Grrrl Victoria, #3, Undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - RMN #7, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Roaring Fork Digest, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rock Candy #3, 4, 5, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rockpile #5, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Sandbox #1, 7, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Scary Doll, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Scour #1, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Second Set Out, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Secret Weapon #3, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - The Secret World of Og #1, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Security Blanket, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Sentimental Suitcase Stickers #1, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Seventeen #1, 3, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sewer, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sex Variants: A Study of Homosexual Patterns, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Shatter, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Short Girl with Short Hair #1, 2, 1995, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Simba #9, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - A Siren Called Fury #1, 2, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Skimpy Faithy, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Slant #5, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Slumber Party Games, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Smile For Me #1, 2, 3, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Some Dumb Girl, 1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Sometimes There Are No Answers, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Spirals Upward #4, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Spirals Upward #2 / Libel #15, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Spirals Upward #5 / Untitled #7, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Spoiler #2, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Sometimes I Feel Like a Blob, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - South Dakota #1, 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - South Dakota Complete, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Spelling Bee #1, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Sprgrl Conspiracy, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Star Gang, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Sticky Crawler #1, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - The Story of O, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subway Sissy, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Take Back Your Life: A Wimmin's Guide to Alternative Health Care, 1990, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Terminology: The Further Adventures of You and Me Part 2, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Terms and Conditions, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - That Grrrl #2, [1993] (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Thinking About Suicide, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - This is the Book of Truth, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - This is My Scream #1, 2, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - This is What I Heard, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - This Scene Makes Me Cream #1, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Thursday, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - TIMTUM, undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Transcending Our Plumbing, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Twenty Bus #1, 3, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Under Control, undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Zine [By Ananda], undated (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - [Untitled], undated (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Untitled Zine [By Ananda], 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Untitled Zine [By Lori], undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Untitled Zines, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - The Urban Hermit #6, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Uterus of the Jungle, undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - The Velveteen Rabbit, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Verses on the Refrigerator Door, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Villa Villa Cola #3, 4, 5, 6, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vital Signs, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Wake Up From Your Nightmare Girl, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - The War on the Disabled: Adding Insult to Injury, [1982] (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Warm Fuzzy #10, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Way Down Low #6, 7, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - We're Not Being Emo It Really Hurts, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Whatcha Thinking? #3, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Where Did Our Love Go?, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Wings Like Thunder, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Winter Garden #1, 2, 3, 1994, 1995, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Wistful, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Women's Her-story, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Women's Psychology: Mental Illness as a Social Disease, [1975] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Words and Smiles #1, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - World's Biggest Bruise #3, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Wreckin Ball #1, 2, 3, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Written on a Body, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - YAWP! #7, 11, 1994, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - The Yellow Rage Vol. 2, Issue 1, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Yield #1, undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Youth Revolution #2, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Zetetic #11, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Zillah #1, undated; 9.0 boxes (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Series II: Ephemera, TBD
  - Flyers, Handouts, and Ephemera, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)